Hello! In this video, I will show you how David
Colombo found a way to steal 55 Tesla cars
from around the world by exploiting insecure
default configuration of TeslaMate application
and ignorance of Tesla car owners. Link to
the original blog post is in the description.
Before we start, we all know that Russia invaded
Ukraine and Ukrainians need our help. That's why I
am donating the income from BBRE premium in March
to Ukraine and charities like Polish Red Cross
supporting people that fled the country.
100% of your subscription goes there.
I cover all the fees and the tax. I also put
links to direct donations in the description.
TeslaMate is a third-party data logger for your
Tesla. It gives you information like location,
charging status, analytics and many more. It's
self-hosted - you need to deploy the code on
your server using docker. It's not an official
Tesla application so after the installation,
TeslaMate will then save the API token
in the database. This will allow it
to pull data about your car from the official
Tesla API. TeslaMate is exposed over port 4000.
If you were using a public IP address, everyone
can see the position and status of your car. It's
quite bad but it becomes even worse. Because on
port 3000, there is an exposed Grafana instance.
It's an open source tool for visualizing data.
TeslaMate downloads the information about your car
from Tesla API while Grafana visualizes
it for you. It makes things like the
history of your journeys or usual parking spots
available to anyone who finds your IP address.
This is a serious privacy breach but it's not the
worst case scenario because the attacker won't
steal or control your car. For that, the attacker
would need a Tesla API key which is stored in the
TeslaMate database. It would allow the attacker
to not only control the air conditioning,
lights or the radio but also unlocking doors and
windows. Although the API key is not enough to
remotely control the accelerator or steer the
car, the attacker could enable keyless driving,
unlock the doors and drive away by himself.
It's that much easier that he knows the
precise location of the car. So leaking this token
would be really, really bad. Data from your Tesla
was stored in Postgres database. Grafana had
access to this database to create visualizations.
The Tesla API key was stored there as well but
obviously, it was not a part of any visualization.
You could use Grafana Explore to write custom
queries and get the key but this required
authentication to Grafana and only the Tesla
owner should have the password to access that.
However, by default Grafana is started
with admin:admin credentials. Of course,
the user should change it after the
installation but many don't bother doing it.
In this particular case, it was possible to
log in to Grafana with the default admin password.
It allowed using Grafana Explore to make
a query to extract the Tesla API key.
Then, you were able to unlock the car and
drive away with someone's Tesla.
David found this bug when doing a security audit.
After that, he also scanned the Internet looking
for other TeslaMate instances exposed with the
default password. He found about 55 of them which
means 55 cars that could have been stolen. He
coordinated the disclosure with Tesla car owners
and revocation of the tokens with the Tesla
security team. You can read the whole story
on the blog. TeslaMate is not an official Tesla
application so this bug is not Elon Musk's fault.
The responsibility for this vulnerability
is on TeslaMate developers who created the
application with insecure defaults, as
well as on Tesla car owners who exposed
the application to the public internet and
didn't change those default credentials.
As for the fix, in TeslaMate application the
Tesla API token is now encrypted in the database
and Grafana doesn't have
the password to decrypt it.
Also, all dashboards and databases of TeslaMate
are now unavailable without authentication.
The fix was introduced in version 1.25.1. So
watch out what you expose to the Internet and
always change default passwords. If you want
to see a $12,000 SSRF in Grafana via a chain
of open redirects, check out this video on your
right. For now thank you for watching and goodbye!